espares.co.uk 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy | eSpares

eSpares Ltd is registered as a Data Controller with the Data Protection Regulator, The Information Commissioner's Office. Our registration reference is Z8481427. eSpares Ltd only collect or use personal and other information relating to you for the purposes indicated in notifications with the Information Commissioner's Office and as detailed in this privacy policy in accordance with all applicable UK & International Laws.

## Why eSpares Ltd collect your information

When eSpares Ltd collects and processes Personal Data it is conducted under the legal basis of performance of a contract to provide goods or services to you that you purchase. 

## What information eSpares Ltd collects & how it is used

**Personal Information** \- When you place an order with eSpares Ltd, your name, e-mail address, home address, delivery address, your contact telephone numbers and payment details, which may include credit or debit card number, expiry date & security code are collected in order to authorise your payment, process and fulfil your orders and to notify you of your order status.

eSpares Ltd may also use this information to carry out security checks which may involve sharing your personal information with credit reference agency Experian to help prevent fraudulent activity.

eSpares Ltd may also use your information to contact you for your views on our services and to notify you occasionally about important changes or developments to the site or to our services. 

If you have provided prior consent eSpares Ltd may also use your name and email address to send you special offers, updates and other promotions.

Consent will be asked for at the point of order and should you decide to order over the phone our operators will also ask you for consent at the appropriate time and refer you to this privacy policy.

Should you later wish to withdraw consent you may do so using the unsubscribe link in any email you receive from us or you may use our contact details to make this request.

**Tracking & Performance Data** \- To improve the design, to tailor content and in order to understand the buying behaviour of users, eSpares Ltd use cookies which are small text files containing tracking information which are stored on your computer’s hard drive. If you set your browser to reject cookies you may be limiting your use of some areas of the website.

Cookies hold the following information:

  * A unique identification number in order to keep track of your order
  * A unique reference number to help identify your order as a whole
  * Product information
  * Computer IP address
  * Web Browser & version
  * Page views & visit information

To find out how to block the use of cookies, please refer to the eSpares Cookie Policy. Please be aware however that blocking the use of cookies may prevent certain functions of our website from working.

**Other Information Pertaining to you** eSpares Ltd may collect other information from you such as any email messages you send to us, transcripts of any live chats you take part in and eSpares Ltd may also record any telephone conversations you may have for training, legal obligations, warranty and improvement purposes.

## Your consumer rights

As a customer of eSpares you have several rights in relation to the processing of your personal information, these are:

**Right to Access** – You may contact eSpares Ltd at any time to ask what information is held about you free of charge. eSpares Ltd are obliged to provide this to you without undue delay up to a maximum of 30 days. Depending on the initial request eSpares Ltd will issue a Subject Access Request (SAR) form in order to better and more quickly identify you and your records. Should eSpares Ltd require more than 30 days to process your request eSpares Ltd will contact you within the 30 day period and let you know.

**Right to Accuracy** – eSpares Ltd takes all necessary steps to ensure information collected is accurate, however should you believe or discover the information held about you is inaccurate you can contact us using the details in the Contact Us section below and ask us to correct it.

**Right to Object** – If you are not satisfied in any way with how eSpares Ltd is processing your information you may communicate using the details/methods provided in the Contact Us section and explain why you object. You may ask eSpares Ltd to restrict or completely stop processing your information. Dependent on the legal basis upon which we are processing it, if eSpares Ltd should not agree to this we will let you know together with the reason why. If you are still not satisfied with our response you may then further appeal this decision by escalating the matter to the ICO whose details are also listed in the Contact Us section.

**Right to Erasure** – You may ask eSpares Ltd to remove all information that relates to you using the details listed in the Contact Us section. Dependent on the legal basis upon which your personal data is being processing should we not agree to this eSpares Ltd will let you know together with the reason why. If you are still not satisfied with the response you may then further appeal this decision by escalating the matter to the ICO whose details are also listed in the Contact Us section. 

**Right to Portability** – You can ask eSpares Ltd to provide any information held about you to another organisation in a universally compatible format. Again you may make this request using the details shown in the Contact Us section. 

## Contact us

You can exercise any of the rights listed above, this is known as a Data Subject Request (DSR) and should be made in writing by completing the form available as a PDF here%2024.10.18.pdf)

This should be printed, completed, signed & returned to eSpares Ltd together with 2 forms of ID, one of which must include your address.

Proofs of identity can include:

  * Your full name and address
  * Your Order Reference Number
  * Birth Certificate
  * Passport
  * Driver's License
  * Credit or debit card statement
  * Utility bill
  * Child benefit book
  * Pension book

Return this information to us by post:

Data Protection Office  
eSpares Ltd.  
Connect House  
Small Heath Business Park  
Talbot Way  
Birmingham  
B10 0HJ

Alternatively you can email us using: [dpo@espares.co.uk](mailto:dpo@espares.co.uk)

We recommend that postal communications are sent by Recorded Delivery, but this is not compulsory.

We will process your request and respond to you no later than 30 days after receipt of your communication.

Should you not be satisfied with eSpares decision you may of course escalate the matter to:

The Information Commissioners Office (ICO)  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF  
Tel: 0303 123 1113

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

eSpares Ltd may make changes every now and then to its privacy policy & terms & conditions, it is your responsibility to familiarise yourself with the latest versions prior to using our website and our services. 

## We are a secure site

eSpares Ltd uses various organisational and technical measures to protect your personal information and is proud to be certified against BSI EN ISO9001 for business processes.

**Organisational Measures** – eSpares Ltd have company policies and handling procedures in place which employees and business partners with whom we may share your information must follow. Regular training is also undertaken to ensure policy and procedures and all applicable regulations and laws are followed. 

**Access Control & Authentication** – eSpares Ltd use access control systems to ensure only authorised employees and business partners have access to your information that is limited to what is needed for carrying out their job. Each individual with access has to provide access credentials in order to gain access to the systems which are monitored. 

Just as eSpares Ltd employees and business partners can gain access to your personal information, eSpares Ltd site may also provide you with account facilities where you can customise and improve your user experience and manage any customisable settings as well as view your own account information.

In order to provide this service eSpares Ltd invite you in the first instance to create a username and password. eSpares Ltd would ask that you maintain the confidentiality of these credentials just as we do ours to help prevent unauthorised access.

eSpares Ltd offer the following tips to keep your log in details secure: 

**Make your password strong** – the longer and more complicated it is the harder it is for others to guess or crack, we suggest using a passphrase (a random selection of words you can easily remember) or why not use a password manager (there are many freely available on line that can create one for you and remember it so that you don’t have to 

**Don't share passwords with anyone** \- even someone you know, passwords can be easily compromised especially if they are known to others

**Don't reuse passwords across multiple on line accounts** \- once a password is compromised a crook can try these credentials on other websites that you may use and gain unauthorised access allowing them learn more about you which can then be used for fraud or identity theft

**Encryption** \- eSpares Ltd use data encryption to ensure safe and secure transactions. eSpares Ltd site is secured using industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or Transport Layer Security (TLS) technology which creates an encrypted link between the web server and your browser ensuring that all data passed between us remains private and secure. 

In order to be able to generate this encrypted link a web server requires an SSL/TLS Certificate. SSL/TLS certificates confirm two essential factors:

  * That you have a secure SSL/TLS (encrypted) link with our website.
  * That the website owner is a valid and legitimate organisation.

**Payment Card Data** – In addition to eSpares Ltd using your payment details to process your order, the organisation that processes the payment together with your card issuer may do additional fraud checks to verify the card and the transaction is legitimate.

Visa & MasterCard in particular may interrupt the order process after you enter your payment details and will prompt you for an additional security password where you are using one of these cards and are enrolled in either the "MasterCard SecureCode" or "Verified by Visa" schemes. Where you are not enrolled you will be asked to enrol. Once this process is completed you will be returned to our website to complete the transaction.

**MasterCard® SecureCode™ Explained**

MasterCard® SecureCode™ is a simple and secure method of payment at online stores, for which you will have a private code known only to you and to your bank. Your SecureCode™ enhances your existing MasterCard® account by safeguarding against unauthorised use of your card when shopping at participating online retailers. Every time you make a payment with these retailers, you will be automatically prompted to enter your own private SecureCode™ - just like entering a PIN at a cash machine. In seconds, you gain added protection while shopping online.

**Verified by Visa Explained**

Verified by Visa is a simple password-protected identity-checking service that takes the risk out of online shopping for both retailers and customers. Retailers are protected against fraudulent transactions and the costs associated with it, while customers can spend with confidence knowing that their payment details are safe.

**Data Storage & Retention** – In order to minimise the risk of exposure to your information Espares Ltd only keep your information for as long as needed in accordance with our policies, industry best practice and to comply with the law. Espares Ltd current internal retention policy is set to a maximum of 7 years this allows us to comply with financial regulations and provides ample time for customers to make enquiries about previous orders and to deal with queries regarding any guarantee and warranty period on products or services sold to you.

Personal information collected via this website is stored on servers located within the EU and therefore is subject to both UK and EU privacy and data protection regulations; eSpares Ltd will not store your information on systems outside of the EU without permission from you unless international data sharing treaties or specialist contracts are in place. 

**Information Sharing** – eSpares Ltd will not disclose your personal information to anyone other than businesses within the CDSL group and to reputable third party contractors engaged by eSpares Ltd to perform a variety of functions such as delivering and processing your orders, assisting with promotions, fraud management, handling complaints or providing technical services such as Live Chat and hosting. 

eSpares Ltd require all such third parties to sign a data sharing agreement which means they agree to treat your personal information as fully confidential and to fully comply with all applicable UK and International data protection laws and consumer legislation from time to time in place. Additionally eSpares Ltd will never sell or pass your personal information to anyone without informing you and gaining your consent. 

**Disclaimer** – eSpares Ltd provide links to other resources & websites such as review sites, social media pages and blogs hosted on other platforms amongst others. By visiting these sites you recognise that these other websites to which eSpares Ltd link to will be governed by their own terms and conditions & privacy policies. We accept no responsibility or liability for the content and data protection policies of websites which are not within eSpares Ltd control. 

This privacy policy may not be applicable in all countries where eSpares Ltd visitors or registered community users reside, security policies may vary according to the individual Internet laws in each host country. 

## Cookie Policy

There are lots of misconceptions about cookies and what they are for. At eSpares Ltd we believe in being open, upfront and honest. In this section eSpares Ltd briefly explains the cookie types used and how they benefit your experience using the website. 

Cookies are used by almost all websites. They contain simple pieces of information and they are downloaded on to your computer when you visit eSpares Ltd website. Cookies are not programs; they are simple text files that can be used by a website for various purposes. At eSpares Ltd we use cookies to ensure our website works efficiently and also to observe visitor behaviour during a session. All the information contained in these cookies is used to ensure the website works correctly, delivers the performance you expect and also to improve the overall experience offered to visitors and customers. Some of these cookies are essential to the operation of the website. 

eSpares Ltd typically use cookies for the following purposes: 

  * To keep track of the items added to your basket.
  * To help identify your order as a whole.
  * To view visitor behaviour and areas of the site visited.
  * To monitor and run advertising and marketing campaigns.
  * To tailor certain content displayed to you.

Overview of the types of cookies used:

**Essential** \- Essential cookies are technical cookies that are required for the operation of the site. Without essential cookies eSpares Ltd sites can't operate properly. Typically these cookies are used to support key functions such as the shopping basket and enhanced features like account sign-in.

**Performance** \- These cookies allow eSpares Ltd to identify and count the number of visitors to our sites and to see how visitors are using the website. This helps to improve the way eSpares Ltd sites work and develop functionality to make shopping with eSpares Ltd a more rewarding experience. 

**Marketing** \- eSpares Ltd uses a range of cookies for marketing purposes. Marketing cookies record your visits to the website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. eSpares Ltd use this information to make the sites and the advertising displayed on them more relevant to your interests. Sometimes eSpares Ltd share anonymous information about your browsing activity recorded using cookies with our advertising partners. They may use this information to advertise products that may interest you on other sites. Please note eSpares Ltd do not share any of your personal or sensitive information as part of this process.

## Use of cookies & consent

As described above eSpares Ltd, like most other websites, use cookies in the operation of our website. By using this website you are agreeing to the use of cookies for the purposes described. If you do not consent to the use of cookies, please refrain from using the site. You can delete and restrict cookie use in your browser:

#### Checking your settings in Internet Explorer 8 and earlier versions

  * Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.
  * There is an option called 'Internet Options' on the list, select this option.
  * This should open a pop up box with lots of tabbed options. Select the 'Privacy' tab from the list.
  * Internet Explorer has a high, medium, low auto-adjust system for internet content handling. You can configure your own settings by clicking the advanced tab and ticking the 'Override automatic cookie handling'.
  * Settings above Medium will disable cookies, Medium or below will enable cookies.

#### Checking your settings in Mozilla Firefox

  * Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.
  * From the list of options on the drop down menu, click on 'Options'.
  * There should be a pop up window appear with tabs along the top. Find the 'Privacy' tab and select this.
  * You should now have some options for 'Tracking' and 'History'. Under the 'History' drop down menu, select 'Use customer' settings for history' if you wish to adjust your cookie settings.

#### Checking your settings in Google Chrome

  * Look for the spanner icon in Chrome and click on this.
  * From this menu, select settings.
  * Within settings you will see tabs on the left hand side. Select the tab called 'Under the Hood'.
  * When this page loads you will see a tab at the top called 'Content Settings' - select this.
  * This brings up your content controls including cookie permissions - select the option you feel most comfortable with.

#### Checking your settings in Safari

  * Locate the Cog icon at the top of your browser and click on this.
  * From the list of options select 'Preferences'.
  * This should open a pop up window with several tabs along the top. From this list select the 'Privacy' option.
  * This will open the tab page that allows you to control the cookie settings on your browser.

#### Checking your settings in Opera

  * Click the Opera file icon in the top left hand corner of your browser.
  * From the drop down list of options, highlight 'Settings' and then scroll across and select 'Preferences'.
  * This should open a pop up window with tabs along the top. Choose the 'Advanced' tab.
  * This shows you the advanced options. On the left hand side there is an option called 'Cookies' - click on this option.
  * This presents the cookie options for your use on this browser.

#### If you have another browser...

Please check the help settings within your browser or use a search engine to find answers on the best way to enable or disable cookies in your chosen browser. Please remember eSpares Ltd are not responsible for the content on external websites.

#### If you want more information...

You can visit the following website for an in-depth guide to cookies and how to control, delete and understand them.

<https://www.aboutcookies.org/>
